I finally got my hands on the rep
Fitness Black Wing and my five favorite
things about it are the 11 gauge steel
build the thousand pound weight capacity
the fact that it's a true FID bench it
has vertical storage and rep even
redesigned their patented zero Gap seat
pad this is a beast of a weight bench
I'm super excited for today's video so
let's get right to it
[Music]
what's up it's Jake back in the barbing
garage gym and for today's video I've
got the rep Fitness Black Wing
adjustable weight bench in for review if
you don't know how this whole process
works in this video today I'm going to
tell you everything there is to know
about this finish we're going to talk
about some pros and cons we're going to
talk about some money most importantly
we're going to talk about who should or
maybe shouldn't purchase this weight
bench now before I start doing all that
I gotta let you know we've reviewed a
ton of other weight benches on
barbin.com and we went ahead and made a
best list of all of our top choices so
if you want to check that out all you
got to do is Google barban best weight
benches it's going to pull right up for
you you can find out for yourself which
ones we like the best
[Music]
all right so in my opinion rep
completely crushed it with this bench so
there's obviously going to be a whole
lot to like about it first of all we got
to talk about the fact that it is a true
FID bench if you don't know what that
means it stands for flat incline and
decline so that's you know referring to
the positions available with this back
pad right here so obviously you know
since it is an adjustable bench it has
more to offer than a standard flat bench
but since it does have you know decline
capabilities it has even more to offer
than a bench that does not all right so
that's going to be really nice right
here you have 12 different back pad
adjustments for you to work with from
negative eight degrees up to 85 degrees
and there's actually laser cut
Engravings right here on the side so
that way you know what angle that you're
working with the seat pad has six
different adjustments itself and this is
using a pop pin style right here now
with the back it's actually a ladder
style adjustment it's really easy for
you to you know just adjust everything
right here but with the seat you're
using a pop pin style now whenever you
go to pull this seat up it's really nice
you actually don't even have to deal
with the pop pin you can just pull it on
up and it's going to adjust accordingly
now to go down you will have to use the
pop pin but
really easy you know for you to use I
also really love the fact that you do
have you know this zero Gap mechanism I
guess you could say right here you know
one of the biggest issues that we've
always had to deal with you know with
adjustable weight benches is having you
know a really big gap right here and
with this technology you know it's just
it's non-existent it doesn't matter what
angle you're using doesn't matter you
know what exercise you're doing you're
never going to have to deal with that
and I really like how rep redesigned
this right here so now you have this pop
pin on the side right here and you just
pull it out and you can slide your bench
seat pad back and forth originally with
the ab5000 which was the first bench
that had this that pop pin was
underneath so it made it a little bit
more difficult to reach at certain times
and you couldn't really I mean you could
it was just kind of hard for you to sit
on it reach underneath and kind of you
know slide it around now I can just sit
right here I can pull this out and I can
slide back and forth super easy for me
to do the Black Wing does have a
thousand pound weight capacity and
that's because it's made from 11 gauge
steel which 11 gauge steel is top tier
cream of the crop whatever you want to
call it you know your own adjective
whatever it is that's the nicest quality
you could ask for with a weight bench
especially at home you know a lot of
times you don't get that so it's really
nice that you're going to get that right
here you do have vertical storage so
there's a little bit of a plastic piece
right here on the back that's going to
allow you to have that vertical storage
it's going to be awesome for anybody
who's tight on space and really just in
general just to make more room for you
to do additional exercises especially
you know something that's requiring you
to be on the floor whatever that is now
rep did you know like I said knock it
out of the park there's a lot of fine
details with this bench right here I
really love the fact that they you know
have this knurled handle on the front
and also I love where it's positioned
this is a pretty heavy weight bench it's
heavier than the ab5000 which this is
basically an iteration of the 5000 and
the 5200 there's you know Concepts from
both of them that rep kind of combined
to put into this one bench right here
and with the 5000 you had a bit of a
stem of a handle I guess you could say
that kind of was underneath the actual
seat so it was kind of hard for you to
reach it also you know made the bench
feel really heavy and it is about 115
pound bench this one's heavier it's
about 130 pounds but because of where
that handle is it doesn't feel as if
it's 130 pounds now it's still heavy but
you're able to get better leverage able
to reach it better and plus that
narrowed handle is just really nice to
grip you also have knurled handles right
here for the ladder adjustment that's
really nice too and you don't always
have to grab it especially when you go
to pull it up you can just pull it up
and it's just gonna you know slide into
all these hooks right here but it's
still really cool kind of adds to the
aesthetic a little bit and speaking of
Aesthetics I mean this is this is a
beautiful weight bench this is a
beautiful weight bench obviously I have
the white one but there's six different
the five different that you can choose
from it's really cool and really for me
when it comes to those cons it's really
just money you know this bench is going
to cost you about 600 bucks I'm gonna
expand on the value and everything but
you can definitely find some cheaper
weight benches out there if you don't
want to spend 600 on just a weight bench
it's also heavy as I mentioned this
weighs 131 pounds not everybody wants to
be you know lugging that around their
home gym you know obviously find you
know some that are going to be a lot
lighter and then also this could be a
little bit nitpicky but you know this is
also just my opinion here when you are
in that decline position you know
obviously there's nothing holding in
your legs right here so for me sometimes
I feel as if
I'm afraid I'm gonna slide down the
bench I'm afraid I'm not you know fully
secured and my legs are locked in and
everything so it would be nice if there
was somehow some way they could fashion
you know some leg rollers that could be
attached down here at least maybe not
here at all the times because it does
kind of get in the way but I think
that'd be a really cool Improvement I
guess you could say with this bench
other than that it's pretty much it as I
said rep has crushed this weight bench
all right
okay so once again the rep Fitness Black
Wing is going to run you right around
600 now it comes stock with a 12 inch
wide back pad and the widest part of the
seat pad is also 12 inches but if you
have a wider back and you want a wider
pad well there's a 14 inch wide option
it's going to run you about an extra 20
bucks or so plus there's also the
optional leg roller attaches to the back
of it right here it's going to run you
about 110 dollars so you could spend as
much as 730 dollars on this fish now
obviously 730 dollars is a lot of money
for a weight bench but so is 600 so
while this bench is pretty much one of
one in my opinion I mean this is one of
the most stout one of the nicest weight
benches that I've ever reviewed
that being said that doesn't necessarily
mean it's the best option for everybody
all right so first of all your budget
doesn't you know can't if you don't have
enough room in your budget for a 600
weight bench one of my personal
favorites is another one from rep it's
the ab 3000 2.0 it's going to run you
around right around 320 bucks it's a
full FID bench it has leg rollers built
into the front thousand pound weight
capacity 11 gauge steel build it's a
really nice weight bench it just you
don't have the zero Gap mechanism right
here now
this is rep's most expensive bench all
right so and since it's you know kind of
an iteration I guess you could say of
the 5000 and the 5200 kind of talk about
those prices for a little bit so the
ab5000 typically you know it used to be
around 600 bucks right now it's around
450 so you can kind of expect it to be
you know in that kind of range right
there now the 5000 is going to run you
right around 450 as well and the 5200 is
actually right around
550 bucks
those are both expensive as well all
right now one more thing I want to
compare to right here is the Rogue manta
ray so the manta ray that's rogue's new
you know pride and joy right now their
weight bench that's around 995 dollars
yeah that's right 995 that's a whole lot
of money for a weight bench so if you
want to you know pin those two head to
head I think you're definitely getting
you know a better deal with actually
with this one right here as compared to
that manta ray because you have more
backpack adjustments more seat pad
adjustments and you have that zero Gap
mechanism so long story short if you
have the budget to purchase a 600 weight
bench you're absolutely going to be
getting your money's worth you have so
many different adjustments you can work
with you know super high quality it's
going to last you a lifetime it really
is going to be the only weight bench
that you ever need to purchase that
being said if you don't have 600 to
spend on just one weight bench not
everybody does not everybody you know
has that kind of budget to work with
definitely go and find yourself a
cheaper option
[Music]
all right so y'all know me you know I
love demonstrating how equipment works
but I'm also going to talk about you
know some of the construction as well so
first things first show you how to
adjust the back pad it's really easy
just pull up now you can also grab these
steel handles right here make it a
little bit easier and you're good to go
now while I got you here this is the
actual vertical storage right here you
got this little plastic piece right here
you got to install it
in total it's only took me around 20 to
25 minutes to assemble it's really easy
honestly now this is so great right here
because it's going to protect this back
pad right here from any type of wear and
tear and really allows you to have that
vertical storage now you can do vertical
storage with a lot of other weight
benches as well but since if they don't
have that you know this pad's just going
to get unnecessary wear and tear and you
obviously you don't want that while I
still got you here this is where that
leg roller attachment would go so you
basically unscrew both of these I'm not
going to do it fully unscrew both of
those you pull this plastic piece out
and you toss it in there and tighten
these back up and it's locked into place
all right so if we drop back down here
you have your uhmw rollers right here
they don't actually roll but you know
that is protecting the steel right here
from any type of scratches paint
chipping all of that that's a nice thing
now as you see you do have your laser
cut Engravings right here it's not for
the in between you know adjustments but
it's really nice you know exact exactly
you know where everything is positioned
so right here on this hinge you have
these bearings right here and actually
there's a spot right here for you to
grease them which is really you know
unusual with weight benches
it's really nice though it's going to
take a long time before you actually
have to grease this bench but you know
if that time ever comes it's nice that
you can do that right there so we'll go
ahead
slide this guy right on back down here
and look just to show you you do have
you know that declines is negative eight
degrees right there all right so go back
to flat as you can see look we have this
Gap right here a lot of weight benches
you know that's the Gap that you're
working with maybe you know a little bit
more narrow but with this bench you
don't have to worry about that because
you have this pop pin right here and you
can slide it in and you're good to go
and that's at every single angle here
I'll show you another one real quick
actually you know what I'll do decline
we'll do the decline since we just had
it there
still have that Gap
got to pull up on the seat excuse me
and there you go you're not going to
have to deal with that and actually you
can go a little bit closer so that's
really cool no matter what angle you're
at you're never going to have to deal
with that which I just personally love
so basically you know I just showed you
you do have that pop pin right here you
just pull it out and slide it and that's
going to be awesome right there let's go
ahead and pull this bad boy up remember
it weighs 131 pounds but because of
where this handle is
it doesn't make it feel that heavy so
it's a 25 millimeter knurled handle it
feels just like their hex dumbbells the
handle and their hex dumbbells you know
it's going to give you a really solid
grip and that's definitely something
that you want so right here underneath
this front foot you do have rubber
that's going to allow the bench to
essentially grip the floor and you know
that's a good thing it's going to add to
the overall stability and prevent any
type of wobble and then plus you have
rubber down here on this back foot and
that's just doubling down on it right
there and since this is in fact a closed
ladder system you know as you see this
back pad is not gonna you know come out
from the rest of the bench and kind of
you know be at a weird angle and
potentially fall so that's really nice
and also with these wheels
forgot to mention that
with these wheels it's actually flat
back here
and this is actually adding to that
stability as you go and store it
vertically so remember like I said
weighs 130 pounds
you know it does have 11 gauge steel
build and it has a thousand pound weight
capacity now as far as the actual
dimensions go it's going to take up
about
10.7 almost 11 square feet right so
about 59 and a half inches long which is
pretty big but this actually can kind of
act as its own flat bench if you want to
move you know further down and maybe not
even sit on the actual you know seat pad
right there and then because of this
back foot it's pretty wide it's almost
26 inches I think it's 25.8 so you know
it's going to be really really sturdy as
you're working out and here I'll go
ahead and show you I know I don't have
any dumbbells in my hands or anything
but you know if you're in that decline
position you know as you see there's
really nowhere for my feet to go and you
know it's probably going to be fine in
the long run but you know if you're
sitting here working out
it's hard to keep your body kind of in
place on its own so that's why I think
it would be so beneficial to have the
leg rollers kind of built in right here
yeah you can get the other one and kind
of position it the other way and do your
workouts that way but having that right
there like with the ab 3000 2.0
that would be such a nice thing it would
make you know using this angle right
here so much better so much more safe
and you know all that stuff so
everything's said and done this is a
really really solid weight bench and I'm
pretty pumped about it
[Music]
foreign
would want to purchase this weight bench
but since there's really only one reason
why somebody wouldn't want to purchase
it let's talk about that first and
really it's just the money it's the 600
weight bench could be 730 bucks as I
mentioned earlier
not everybody has that budget and that's
okay you know there's plenty of other
weight benches that are you know a
fraction of this price tag right here
that are still solid and they're still
going to last you a really long time so
basically that's all there is to it you
know if you don't have 600 to spend on
just one thing in general you know
especially a weight bench definitely go
find yourself a cheaper option now when
it comes to those who would want to
purchase this well obviously you got to
have the budget for it right but if you
do then you're going to be happy for
happy with it in the long run it's going
to definitely hold up its own value
because it's going to last you really
long time potentially your entire
fitness journey plus there's so much
versatility
you know you have 12 different back pad
angles six different seat pad angles and
you can even purchase that optional leg
roller attachment remember it is an
extra 110 bucks but it's going to allow
you to incorporate you know decline
sit-ups and some other exercises within
your workout regimen plus it has you
know vertical storage so if you're
somebody who's tight on space or just
wants to make the most of your space in
general that's going to be a really nice
thing for you as well and then plus you
know you do have this awesome zero Gap
seat right here so if you're just
absolutely fed up with dealing with that
awkward gap between the seat and the
back pad this is one of the best options
for you
foreign
over the rep Fitness Black Wing yes this
is going to cost you a pretty penny but
if you have the budget for it I
definitely think you're going to be
thrilled with it in the long run because
it is made from that high quality 11
gauge steel it does have that thousand
pound weight capacity there's so many
different angles for you to work with
and it has this awesome zero Gap seat
pad right here thanks for watching y'all
hope this video was really helpful and I
was able to break down everything there
is to know about this weight bench as
always keep your eyes peeled for my next
video but for now why don't you head
over to barbin.com because we have a
full written article about this weight
bench all you got to do is search bar
Bend rep Fitness Blackwing adjustable
weight bench review that article is
going to pull right up for you you can
read over every single thing we talked
about here today I'll catch y'all next
time
[Music]
thank you